Partial Guide to the Memorial Library of Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Three Gospel Hymns for Orchestra. / HELM, EVERETT, MLM 499A
  First draft of the second movement. 12 pages.
- Three Gospel Hymns for Orchestra. / HELM, EVERETT, MLM 499B
  Pencil sketch of the first movement of 8 pages.
- Sonata for Flute and Piano. / HELM, EVERETT, MLM 499C
  Second draft of 53 pages.
- Poëme d'amour à Rosalie. / HENSELT, ADOLPH VON (1814-1889), MLM 500
  Manuscript fragment signed. Berlin, August 1850. 1 leaf (1 page) 191/4 x 241/4 cm. The other side of this leaf contains the ""Thème du choeur des sylphes"" by Hector Berlioz.
- The debutante. / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 501
  The original manuscript signed. 1914. 279 leaves (425 pages) 271/2 x 35, 28 x 37cm. With this is the original manuscript of ""Selections from 'The debutante' arranged from the original score by Harold Sanford."" 22 leaves (39 pages) 28 x 37 cm. The work and
- Babette. / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 502
  A romantic comic opera. Book & lyrics by Harry B. Smith. Music by Victor Herbert. Vocal score. New York, M. Witmark & Sons, c1903. Pl. no. 5976. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. The inscription includes five bars of music from the score.
- Madeleine. / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 503
  A lyric opera in one act. Adapted from the French of Decourcelles & Thibaut by Grant Stewart. Music by Victor Herbert. Vocal score. New York, G. Schirmer, c1913. Pl. no. 24218. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. The inscription includes three bars of music from the score. Madeleine was performed for the first time at the Metropolitan Opera House, January 24, 1914, with Mme. Frances Alda in the title role.
- Mlle. Modiste. / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 504
  A comic opera. Books & lyrics by Henry Blossom. Music by Victor Herbert. Vocal score. New York, M. Witmark & Sons, c1905. Pl. no. 7295. First edition. Inscribed: ""To my friend A de Novellis, the excellent conductor. Victor Herbert, May 1906."" The inscription includes two bars of music from the score.
- Natoma, an opera in three acts." / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 505
  The book by Joseph D. Redding. The music by Victor Herbert. New York, G. Schirmer, c1911. Pl. no. 22341. First edition. Piano and vocal score. This is copy no. 29 of a special edition of 250 copies printed on Old Stratford paper and signed by the composer and librettist. Presented for the first time at Philadelphia, February 25, 1911.
- Photograph portrait of the composer. / HERBERT, VICTOR (1859-1924), MLM 505A
  Inscribed to Lon F. Gottschalk, November 1912. The inscription includes three bars from Natoma.
- Lodovic. / HEROLD, LOUIS JOSEPH FERDINAND (1791-1833), MLM 506
  Opéra comique en 2 actes. Paroles de M. St. Georges. Musique d' Hérold et de F. Halévy. Paris, Maurice Schlesinger [ca. 1833] Pl. nos. 1430, 1429-1 to 1429-14. First edition. Inscribed by Halévy. Piano and vocal score. Presented for the first time at Paris, May 16, 1833. Hérold died January 19, 1833 and this opera was completed by Halévy. Wotquenne, 2019.
- Trois caprices pour le pianoforte dédiés a son ami Frédéric Chopin par Ferdinand Hiller. Op. 12. / HILLER, FERDINAND (1811-1885), MLM 507
  Original manuscript signed. 10 leaves (title, 15 pages) 24X 31 cm.
- Apollo and the seaman. / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 508
  A poem on immortality by Herbert Trench. Set as a dramatic symphony by Joseph Holbrooke (Op. 51) Full score. London, Novello, c1908. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- The bathers, opus 74, no. 1." / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 509
  Original manuscript signed. 6 leaves (6 pages) 27x32 cm. Piano and voice with flute obbligato. The poem is by Gerald Cumberland.
- Prelude to Dylan. / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 510
  A music drama in three acts. Poem by T. E. Ellis. Arranged for the full score (Op. 53). London, Boosey [ca. 1914] Pl. no. J.H. 4. At head of title: Joseph Holbrooke. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Les hommages. / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 511
  Grand suite no. III. Arranged for string orchestra. Opus 37. Original manuscript signed. 27 leaves (54 pages) 23 x 291/2 cm. Contents: ""Festival"" (""March heroïque""); ""Serenata""; ""Elégie""; ""Introduction & Danse russe."" Inserted is an autograph letter signed, written by the composer to [William] Saunders, April 4, presenting the original manuscript to him. In this letter Holbrooke says, 'I always burn my early MS. [sic]!""
- Sextet, no. 1, opus 20." / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 512
  Slavonic dance. Original manuscript signed. 10 leaves (title-page, 18 pages). An arrangement for piano duet.
- Symphonic quartet, opus 37, no. 2." / HOLBROOKE, JOSEF (1878-), MLM 513
  Original manuscript signed. 1904. 33 leaves (title-page, 63 pages). Composed in 1896-1898. Presented for the first time at Bechstein, December 10, 1903. Inscribed to William Wallace by the composer.
- Lutèce. / HOLMES, AUGUSTA MARY ANNE (1847-1903), MLM 514
  Symphonie dramatique. Poëme et musique par Augusta Holmes. Partition chant & piano. Paris, Choudens Père & Fils [1879] P1. no. A. C. 4878. First edition. Inscribed to Emmanuel Chabrier by the composer.
- Les aventures du roi Pausole. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 515
  Opérette en 3 actes de Albert Willemetz, d'après le roman de Pierre Louÿs. Musique de Arthur Honegger. Partition piano et chant. Paris, Francis Salabert, c1930. Pl. no. E. A. S. 6333. First edition. Presented for the first time at Paris, 1930.
- Le cantique des cantiques. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 516
  Ballet en deux actes. Argument poétique de Gabriel Boissy. Musique de Arthur Honegger. Sur les rythmes de Serge Lifar. La partition piano et chant. Paris, Heugel [1938] Pl. no. H. 31029. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Thomas by the composer.
- Judith. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 517
  Drame biblique en trois actes. Musique de Arthur Honegger. Paroles de René Morax. Paris, Maurice Senart, c1925. Pl. no. E. M. S. 6718.
- Judith. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 518
  Opéra sérieux en trois actes et cinq tableaux. Paroles de René Morax. Paris, Maurice Senart [c1925] Pl. no. E.M.S. 6938. At head of title: Arthur Honegger. First edition. Presented for the first time at Monte Carlo, in 1926.
- Les mille et une nuits. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 519
  Origina1 manuscript signed. 2 leaves (4 pages) 27 x 33 cm. A preliminary study. Piano score with text and synopsis for orchestration on the first page.
- Le roi David. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 520
  Psaume dramatique en deux parties de René Morax. Musique de Arthur Honegger. Partition pour chant et piano. Lausanne, Foetisch Frères, c1921. Pl. No. F. 1990 F. First edition. Presented for the first time at Mezières, Switzerland, June 11, 1921.
- Sonatine pour deux violins. / HONEGGER, ARTHUR (1892-), MLM 521
  Paris, Editions de la Sirène, c1922. Pl. no. ED 113 LS. At head of title: Arthur Honegger. Inscribed to M. Carembat by the composer.
- The emerald isle: the caves of Carrig-Cleena. / HOOD, BASIL (1864-1917), MLM 522
  Written by Basil Hood. Composed by Arthur Sullivan and Edward German. London, Chappell, 1901. First edition of the libretto.
- Berceuse for piano. / Howe, Mary, MLM 522A
  Autograph ms. signed.
- Titania. / HUE, GEORGES ADOLPHE (1858-), MLM 523
  Drame musical en trois actes de Louis Gallet et André Corneau. Musique de Georges Hüe. Partition piano et chant. Paris, Choudens, c1903. Pl. no. A. C. 11,298. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. de Craponne by the composer. Mlle. de Craponne played the role of Robin.
- A complete theoretical and practical course of instruction on the art of playing the piano forte, commencing with the simplest elementary principles, and including every information requisite to the most finished style of performance, written by J. N. Hummel." / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 524
  London, T. Boosey [1828]. Hummel's Piano school was one of the first to advocate a rational method of fingering. Inserted are two autograph letters. Gräz, 17/9/1832; Weimar, 28/9/1832.
- Concert für das Piano-forte, mit Begleitung zweyer Violinen; Viola und Violoncello (nebst einigen Blassinstrumenten ad libitum) von J. N. Hummel. 73tes Werk." / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 525
  Wien, S. A. Steiner [1816] Pl. no. 2500. First edition. Original manuscript of a dance composed about 1830 (cf. separate entry, see item no. 526).
- [Dance] / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 526
  Original manuscript. ca. 1830. 1 leaf (1 page) 33 x 24cm. Concert für das Piano-forte, opus 73. See item no. 525.
- Etudes pour le piano-forte par J. N. Hummel. / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 527
  Oeuvre 125. Vienne, Tobias Haslinger [1833] Pl. no. T. H. 6551. First edition.
- Autograph letter signed. / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 527A
  To Sir George Smart, London, ca. April 10, 1833.
- Repertoire de musique pour les dames. / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 528
  Ouvrage périodique et progressif, composé par Jean Nep. Hummel. A Vienne, l'Auteur [182-] Année I, cahiers 1-12 in II parts (8-9 is a double issue) each with its own title-page. Each part signed by the composer.
- [Variations] / HUMMEL, JOHANN NEPOMUK (1778-1837), MLM 528A
  Theme varie pour le piano forte. Oeuvre 34. no.1 La sentinelle. Offenbach s/M, J. Andre [181]
- Hänsel und Gretel. / HUMPERDINCK, ENGELBERT (1854-1921), MLM 529
  Dichtung von Adelheid Wette, geb. Humperdinck. Märchenspiel in drei Bildern von Engelbert Humperdinck. Vollständige Orchester-Partitur. Mainz, B. Schott's Söhne, 1894. Pl. no. 25617. First edition. Presented for the first time at Weimar, December 23, 1893. Wotquenne, 2414.
- Hänsel und Gretel. / HUMPERDINCK, ENGELBERT (1854-1921), MLM 530
  Märchenspiel in drei Bildern von Adeiheid Wette. Musik von Engelbert Humperdinck. Vollständiger Klavierauszug mit Text. Mainz, B. Schott's Söhne, 1894. Pl. no. 25618. First edition.
- Die Heirat wider Willen. / HUMPERDINCK, ENGELBERT (1854-1921), MLM 531
  Komische Oper in drei Aufzugen, frei nach einem Lustpiel des A. Dumas. Klavierauszug mit text von Alfred Brüggemann und Fritz Zech. Leipzig, Max Brockhaus, 1905. Pl. no. M. B. 466. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. The inscription includes two bars of music from the score. Presented for the first time at Berlin, 1905.
- Königskinder. / HUMPERDINCK, ENGELBERT (1854-1921), MLM 532
  Ein deutsches Märchen in drei Akten von Ernst Rosmer. Musik von Engelbert Humperdinck. Einleitung züm III Abt. Leipzig, Max Brockhaus [c1896] P1. no. M. B. 280 III. First edition. Orchestral score. Presented for the first time at New York City, December 28, 1910.
- Das Maedchen an ihren Geliebten. / Hurka., MLM 532A
  Eine Antwort auf Overbecks Schiffahrt von Werder. Hamburg, Aug. Bohme [n.d.]
- Concerto pour violoncelle et orchestre d'instruments à vent. Réduction pour violoncelle et piano. / IBERT, JACQUES (1890-), MLM 533
  Paris, Heugel [c1926] Pl. no. H. 29,263. At head of title: Jacques Ibert. Inscribed to M. Piatigorsky by the composer.
- Le Ballade de la geole de Reading. / IBERT, JACQUES (1890-), MLM 533A
  Paris, Alphonse Leduc [c1924] Pl. no. A. L. 12,616.
- Escales. mcmxxii. / IBERT, JACQUES (1890-), MLM 533B
  Reduction de l'orchestre pour piano 4 mains par l'auteur. [Paris] Alphonse Leduc [c1924] Pl. no. A. L. 16,723.
- Le roi d' Yvetot. / IBERT, JACQUES (1890-), MLM 534
  Opéra-comique en quatre actes. Livret de Jean Limozin et André de la Tourrasse. Musique de Jacques Ibert. La partition chant et piano. Paris [1930] Pl. no. H. 30,115. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, January 6, 1930. See also RAVEL, MAURICE JOSEPH (1875-1937) L'éventail de Jeanne.
- The mariner's toast, a national song as sung by Mr. Bridgewater at the Canterbury catch club, the words by I. R. Stevens, the music by Wm. Jackson, Masham." / JACKSON, WILLIAM (1815-1866), MLM 548
  Original manuscript signed.3 leaves (title-page, 5 pages) 241/2 x 30 cm.
- Ouverture zu einem Gozzi'schen Lustspiel fur gorsses Orchester. / Joachim, Joseph (1831-1907), MLM 548A
  Partitur.Berlin, N. Simrock. c1902. Pl. no. 11686.
- J. Rosamond Johnson's (Musical episode) ""De chain gang"" based on work songs of the Southland for male voices with descriptive continuity and light effects." / JOHNSON, JOHN ROSAMOND (1873-), MLM 549
  New York, Handy Brothers [c1938] First edition. Inscribed for the collection by Mr. Johnson.
- Sixteen new Negro spirituals arranged and adapted by J. Rosamond Johnson. [New York, Handy Brothers, c1939] First edition. Inscribed for the collection by Mr. Johnson." / JOHNSON, JOHN ROSAMOND (1873-), MLM 550
- The favourite songs in the opera call'd Andromaca by Sigr. Jomelli. / JOMMELLI, NICCOLO (1714-1774), MLM 551
  London, I. Walsh [ca. 1756] First edition. Text in Italian. The last aria is by Lampugnani [LAMPUGNANI, GIOVANNI BATTISTA (1706-ca. 1772)].
- The favourite songs in the opera call'd Orazio. / JOMMELLI, NICCOLO (1714-1774), MLM 552
  London, I. Walsh [ca. 1755] First edition. Text in Italian. A pasticcio by Jomelli, Fini, Macchari, Resta and Paradies.
- Le chevalier Jean. / JONCIERES, VICTORIN (real name, FELIX LUDGER ROSSIGNOL) (1859-1903), MLM 553
  Drame lyrique en 4 actes. Paroles de Louis Gallet et Edouard Blau. Musique de Victorin Joncières. Partition chant & piano. Paris, Léon Grus [1885] Cover title. Pl. no. L. G. 4267. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, March 11, 1885. Wotquenne, 2875.
- Dimitri. / JONCIERES, VICTORIN (real name, FELIX LUDGER ROSSIGNOL) (1859-1903), MLM 554
  Opéra en 5 actes. Paroles de MM. H. de Bornier et A. Silvestre. Musique de Victorin Joncières. Partition piano et chant. Paris, Léon Grus [ca. 1890] Pl. no. L. G. 5002. At head of title: 2me édition. Inscribed to Em. Chabrier by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, May 5, 1876. Wotquenne, 2873.
- Le reine Berthe. / JONCIERES, VICTORIN (real name, FELIX LUDGER ROSSIGNOL) (1859-1903), MLM 555
  Opéra en deux actes. Paroles de Jules Barbier. Musique de Victorin Joncières. Partition réduite pour piano et chant par L. Delahaye. Paris, Léon Grus [1878] Pl. no. L. G. 3532. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, December 27, 1878. Wotquenne, 2874.
- San Toy; or, The emperor's own." / Jones, Sidney, MLM 555A
  A Chinese musical comedy. Words by Edward Morton. Lyrics by Harry Greenbank & Adrian Ross. Music by Sidney Jones...London, Keith, Prowse, c1899. Pl. no. K. P. & Co. 1309.
- Fantaisie brillante pour le piano sur les motifs de La barcarolle de D. F. E. Auber par F. Kalkbrenner. / KALKBRENNER, FRIEDRICH WILHELM MICHAEL (1788-1849), MLM 556
  Opéra 176. Paris, E. Troupenas [ca. 1845] Pl. no. E. T. et Cie. 1802. First edition. Inscribed to Zimmermann by the composer.
- Ben Bolt, or Oh! don't you remember." / KNEASS, NELSON, MLM 557
  Ballad. Sung by Miss Clara Bruce. Composed by Nelson Kneass. Louisville, W. C. Peters [c1848] Pl. no. 1138. First edition. The words are by Thomas Dunn English.
- Sinfonietta für grosses Orchester. / KORNGOLD, ERICH WOLFGANG (1897-), MLM 558
  Op. 5. Partitur. Mainz, B. Schott's Söhne [1914] At head of title: Ernest Wolfgang Korngold. Pl. no. 29800. First edition. Inscribed to Alexander v. Zemlinsky by the composer.
- Sonate für das Pianoforte. / KORNGOLD, ERICH WOLFGANG (1897-), MLM 559
  Op. 2, No. 2 in E-dur. Mainz, B. Schott's Söhne [1911] Pl. no. 29400. At head of title: Erich Wolfgang Korngold. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Le beau Nicolas. / LACOME D'ESTALEUX, PAUL JEAN JACQUES (1838-1920), MLM 560
  Opéra-comique en 3 actes. Paroles de MM. A. Vanloo et Eug. Leterrier. Musique de P. Lacome. Partition chant et piano. Réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [1880] Pl. no. E. F. & C. 487. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Madame Boniface. / LACOME D'ESTALEUX, PAUL JEAN JACQUES (1838-1920), MLM 561
  Opéra-comique en 3 actes. Paroles de MM. Ernest Depré et Charles Clairville. Musique de P. Lacome. Partition piano et chant réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [1885] Pl. no. E. F. & C. 801. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer.
- La nuit de Saint-Jean. / LACOME D'ESTALEUX, PAUL JEAN JACQUES (1838-1920), MLM 562
  Opéra comique en 1 acte. Poëme de MM. A. Delacour & J. de Lau-Lusignan (tiré d'une nouvelle d'Erckmann-Chatrian) Partition piano & chant réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [1882] Pl. no. E. F. & C. 689. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer.
- Vingt melodies de P. Lacome. / LACOME D'ESTALEUX, PAUL JEAN JACQUES (1838-1920), MLM 563
  Paris, Enoch Père & Fils [1898] Pl. no.E. P. et F. 250. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer. Piano and vocal score.
- Allegro maestoso pour piano et violon composé par E. Lalo. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 564
  [Oeuvre 2] Paris, L. le Bel [ca. 1850] Pl. no. A. 54. First edition. Inscribed to M. Kaufmann by the composer.
- Au fond des halliers. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 565
  Duo. Paroles de André Theuriet. Musique de E. Lalo. No. 2. Soprano et tenor. Paris, Choudens Père & Fils [1886] Pl. no. A. C. 7480. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Russeil by the composer.
- L'aube noir. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 566
  Original manuscript signed. 4 leaves (4 pages) 27 x 351/2 cm.
- Fantaisie originale pour le violon avec accompagnement de piano par E. Lalo. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 567
  [Oeuvre 1] Paris, L. le Bel [ca. 1848] Pl. no. A. 52. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Fiesque. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 568
  Divertissement pour orchestre par Edouard Lalo. Réduction pour piano seul par J. Massenet. Paris, G. Hartmann [1866] Pl. no. G. H. 284. First edition. Inscribed to Edouard Colonne by the composer. Signed by Colonne.
- Namouna. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 569
  Ballet en 2 actes et 3 tableaux de MM. Ch. Nuitter et Petipa. Musique de Edouard Lalo. Partition pour piano. Paris, J. Hamelle [1882] Pl. no. J. 2633 H. First edition. Inscribed to J. Weber by the composer. The J. Weber to whom this is inscribed may have been Johannes Weber, music critic for Le Temps. Presented for the first time at Paris, 1882.
- Le roi d'Ys. Légende bretonne. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 570
  Opéra en 3 actes & 5 tableaux. Poème de Edouard Beau. Musique de Ed. Lalo. Partition chant & piano. Paris, G. Hartmann [1888] Pl. no. G. H. & Cie. 1745. First edition. Presented for the first time at Paris, May 7, 1888. Wotquenne, 2880.
- 6 romances populaires de P. J. de Béranger. / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 571
  Musique de E. Lalo. no. 1. La pauvre femme, no. 2. Beaucoup d'amour, no. 3. Le suicide, no. 4. Si j'étais petit oiseau, no. 5. Les petits coups, no. 6. Le vieux vagabond. Paris, Mme. Vue. Launer [ca. 1848] First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- [Sonata, opus 72]" / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 572
  Grand duo pour piano et violon. Paris, J. Benacci-Peschier [c1860] Pl. no. B. P. 776. First edition. Inscribed to M. Lubeck by the composer.
- Trio pour piano, violon, et violoncelle, par E. Lalo." / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 573
  Op. 7. Paris, Richault [ca. 1851] Pl. no. R. 10411. First edition. Inscribed ""A son ami Faucheur"" by the composer.
- Trio pour piano, violon et violoncelle, par E. Lalo." / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 574
  Op. 7. Paris, Richault [ca.1851] Pl. no. R. 10411. First edition. Inscribed to M. Morena by the composer.
- 2e. trio pour piano, violon et violoncelle par Edouard Lalo." / LALO, VICTOR ANTOINE EDOUARD (1823-1892), MLM 575
  Paris, J Maho [ca 1859] P1 no J M 43. First edition Inscribed ""A son ami A Faucheur"" by the composer.
- Pomona. / LAMBERT, CONSTANT (1905-), MLM 576
  A ballet in one act. Theme by Thomas McGreevy. Choreography by La Nijinska. Music by Constant Lambert. Pianoforte duet arrangement by the composer. [London] Oxford University Press [c1928] First edition.
- The Rio Grande. / LAMBERT, CONSTANT (1905-), MLM 577
  Poem by Sacheverell Sitwell set for chorus, orchestra, and solo pianoforte by Constant Lambert. German version by Beryl de Zoete. London, Oxford University Press [1929] First edition. No. 40 of a special numbered edition of 75 copies. Signed by the author and composer.
- Romeo and Juliet. / LAMBERT, CONSTANT (1905-), MLM 578
  Ballet in two tableaux. Music by Constant Lambert. Choreography by Nijinska. Arrangement for piano solo by the composer. [London] Oxford University Press [c1926] First edition. Inscribed to R. O. Morris by the composer.
- Sonata for pianoforte, by Constant Lambert." / LAMBERT, CONSTANT (1905-), MLM 579
  London, Oxford University Press [c1930] First edition. Cover-title. Inscribed to R. O. Morris by the composer.
- Terpsichoren Walzer, opus 12." / LANNER, JOSEPH FRANZ KARL (1801-1843), MLM 580
  Original manuscript signed. [ca. 1825] 8 leaves(14 pages) 32 x 25 cm. Full orchestral score consisting of a short introduction and six waltzes. Lanner, one of the founders of Viennese dance music, alternated with Johann Strauss as conductor at the court balls. [also a letter in German (dealer's letter)]
- Chants de la mer et des villages pour voix graves et moyennes. / LAPARRA, RAOUL (1876-1943), MLM 581
  Mélodies sur des poésies de Paul Fort. Paris, Heugel [c1926] Pl. nos. H. 29,387-29,400. At head of title: Raoul Laparra. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Pierre Chereau by the composer. Contents: ""Le vent des forêts,"" ""Le bonheur,"" ""Le dit du Bergerot,"" ""La chanson fatale,"" ""L'épouse châtiée,"" ""La corde,"" ""Le diable dans la nuit,"" ""Les baleines,"" ""J'ai des p'tit's fleurs bleues,"" ""La fille morte dans des amours,"" ""Complainte des soldats,"" ""Les differences,"" ""L'amoureuse,"" ""La chanson des marins hales.""
- Un dimanche Basque (A Basque Sunday). / LAPARRA, RAOUL (1876-1943), MLM 582
  Poème en 4 parties pour orchestre avec piano. Raoul Laparra. Paris, Choudens, c1922. Pl. no. A. C. 15713. First edition. Inscribed to Henri Collet by the composer.
- La Habanera. / LAPARRA, RAOUL (1876-1943), MLM 583
  Drame lyrique en 3 actes. Partition piano et chant réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch, c1907. Pl. no. E. & C. 6574. At head of title: Raoul Laparra. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Albert Carré by the composer. Inserted is an autograph letter signed by Laparra, and addressed to Albert Carré, Director [of the Opéra-Comique] Paris, February 24, 1908. This relates to the first performance of the opera which took place two days later.
- La jota. / LAPARRA, RAOUL (1876-1943), MLM 584
  Conte lyrique en 2 actes. Partition pour piano et chant réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch, c1911. Pl. no. E. & C. 7204. First edition. Inscribed to M. Dupré by the composer. M. Dupré sang the role of El Cabrito in the first performance at the Théâtre National de l'Opéra-Comique, Paris, April 26, 1911.
- La camargo. / LECOCQ, ALEXANDRE CHARLES (1832-1918), MLM 585
  Opéra comique en trois actes. Paroles de MM. At. Vanloo & Ene. Leterrier. Musique de Charles Lecocq. Partition chant & piano arrangée par Léon Roques. Paris, Brandus [1878] Pl. no. 12421. Cover-title. First edition. Inscribed to Chabrier by the composer. Presented for the first time at the Théâtre de la Renaissance, November 20, 1878.
- Fleur de thé. / LECOCQ, ALEXANDRE CHARLES (1832-1918), MLM 586
  Opera-bouffe en 3 actes. Paroles de MM. Alfred Duru et Henri Chivot. Musique de Charles Lecocq. Partition chant et piano arrangée par l'auteur. Paris, G. Brandus et S. Dufour [ca. 1868] Pl. no. B. et D. 11,400. First edition. Performed for the first time at Paris, April 11, 1868.